

## CAMILO ALEJANDRO URIBE VARGAS

+57 3004680847

♥ Medellín, Colombia

Birthday: 23/10/1992

## **PROFILE**

Junior developer with a mechanical/chemical engineering background. I have good analytical skills, and really enjoy problem solving through teamwork. My curiosity and experience in engineering and research have made me an adaptable professional, ready to take on the challenges of the tech industry.

#### SKILLS

- HTML5, CSS
- JavaScript
- Python
- React
- Django

### LANGUAGES

- Spanish (Native)
- English (Advanced)
- French (Intermediate)

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

## RESEARCHER – UNIVERSIDAD NACIONAL DE COLOMBIA September 2019 – July 2021

- Modelling of thermochemical processes in python and MATLAB.
- Data analysis and representation with python (SciPy, Pandas, matplotlib, Seaborn).
- Setting up and managing AWS EC2 Linux instances for chemical dynamics and DFT simulations.
- Development and design of pyrolysis reactors and condensation systems.

## JUNIOR PROJECT ENGINEER – TERMALTEC S.A May 2018- January 2019

- Calculations and design of industrial heating systems for companies and private customers, according to their needs and requirements.
- Technical sales and customer negotiations.

# RESEARCH ASSISTANT – UT INCOMBUSTION February 2016- July 2017

- Energy audits of high-temperature processes in industrial facilities.
- Data analysis and representation. Writing technical reports.
- Presenting results to technical and non-technical audiences.

#### EDUCATION

### COURSERA 2020

IBM Data science professional certificate

## UNIVERSIDAD NACIONAL DE COLOMBIA 2019 - Present

Master's in Chemical engineering

## UNIVERSIDAD DE ANTIOQUIA 2010-2016

Bachelor's degree in Mechanical engineering

Camilo Unila V.